*music*
Thank you.
Well, good morning, Canvas Community Church.
Merry Christmas, everyone.
Thank you all for joining us.
I see lots of, is it that thing?
I see lots of new faces.
I see faces that look like, see, the problem with the glasses is I can see you guys so
much better now.
Just locked in on Matt laughing at me.
This is great.
See lots of new faces.
Looks like loving grandparents, aunts, uncles, nieces, nephews, cousins, friends for our Christmas
play, which we are very excited about, all of us except for Michelle, who I maybe threw
up a couple times this morning.
I'm not sure.
But in all honesty, really looking forward to this morning and everything that you see is
thanks to Michelle's hard work and dedication.
Her team, wonderful team of volunteers.
All of the parents that have supported this whole thing by showing up to many practices, super
thankful for all of you.
Really excited to just see a rendition of the Christmas story from our children this morning.
So if we haven't met yet, my name is Ryan.
I have the privilege of being one of the pastors here, and we're so glad that you could join us.
If you want to let us know that you're a guest, if you're a guest, there should be a connect
card in your bulletin or right there on the screen.
We'd love to hear from you and get you connected to our church in any way that you might want.
There are also, I think there's some, I think there's a program.
So if your kid's name is on the program, you're going to want to save that.
You're going to want to get it laminated.
You're going to want to put it in a memory box.
This is going to be worth some money someday.
So definitely do that.
And I have a couple announcements.
I'm going to hand it over to Pastor Michelle.
We're going to watch a wonderful Christmas play.
And then I'm a pastor, so I can't miss an opportunity to tell you about God's word.
So I'll come back up for a short message after that, and then we will dismiss you all.
So there is a youth parent meeting for middle and high school parents directly after church
right up here, correct, Donovan?
So if you have a middle or high school student, Donovan will love to spend a couple minutes
chatting with you guys up here after service.
Our Christmas Eve service, our candlelight service is at 6 p.m. on, you guessed it, Christmas Eve.
So we'd love to have you here.
If you're a regular Canvas person, if you've been around for a while, I'd love to encourage
you to sit close and sit together so that we can make space for people that might be coming
to our services for the first time.
So Christmas Eve, 6 p.m., if you're a regular, I'd love for you to come a little early, sit
close, find somebody that you know that you wouldn't mind being shoulder to shoulder with
and sit by them.
That would be great.
On the 29th, Sunday the 29th, we will not have an in-person service.
We have an online service, a prerecorded online service that we'd love for you to join us
online, Facebook, YouTube, the website.
We will gather in that way.
If you want to gather together with a small group of people, that's always a great opportunity.
If you want to take communion with your family after that service, that's a great opportunity.
We'd love to have you join us for that.
And I hear children getting restless, so I'm going to hurry.
Yeah, I think that's all I have for now.
So, Michelle, here you go.
Hey, good morning, guys.
If I haven't met you, my name is Michelle Meeks.
I have the extreme privilege of being the children's pastor.
And I am, like, really, really excited for you guys to see this play.
These kids have worked so hard.
We have some incredibly talented kids that you will soon see for yourself.
I do want to thank the parents.
We've been practicing.
The actors have been practicing since October.
And we all know how crazy life is.
So to get your kids here, they worked on their lines.
They worked really hard.
And so, parents, thank you so much for making this a priority.
I want to thank Eric Crosby, who made the manger that you see here.
And then John Foley, the risers that the kids are on.
They both used scrap wood, found anything they could, and built that so that we could make
today happen.
Also want to let you know, one of our main actors, Anna Kucinich, is really sick.
She woke up with a fever of 102.
So we did some very last-minute scrambling to make sure that she had a big part and two solos.
So there are some kids that are filling in that you won't even notice because they are such
rock stars.
They literally came through.
And thank you to those parents that took my panic attack and made me calm down.
So that is all I have for you.
So we're going to get started.
And I hope all of you enjoy.
And I got a story for you.
And the best part is, it really happened.
It was just like any old night in Bethlehem.
Or so we thought.
For in that starry night, a miracle occurred, coming down from heaven in the form of a baby.
We were so surprised that something so important could happen in our sleepy little town.
But the prophet Micah foretold it in the Scriptures when he said that straight out of tiny Bethlehem
would come one who would be ruler over Israel.
And the best part is, it really is.
It's Christmas, make a joyful sound.
It's Christmas, let its praise resound.
It's Christmas.
Goodwill to all the earth, and peace divine.
The role of the earth, rejoice.
It's Christmas time.
So live up your voice and sing out his praise.
It's Christmas, born as the king rejoiced in the day.
It's Christmas, make a joyful sound.
It's Christmas, let its praise resound.
It's Christmas, when you talk your voice and sing out its praise.
It's Christmas, for us to gain, rejoice in the day.
It's Christmas, make a joyful sound.
It's Christmas, let its praise be sound.
It's Christmas.
It's Christmas, when you talk your voice and sing out its praise.
It's Christmas, for us to gain, rejoice in the day.
It's Christmas, make a joyful sound.
It's Christmas, let its praise be sound.
It's Christmas.
Good morning friends, up and at them.
The inn is nearly filled to capacity, and there's work to do.
Rise and shine, my fellow world changers.
There's just something about today.
I feel my bones.
It's a beautiful day, and we get to shine.
It's not that I don't agree with you, it's just, my body hasn't quite caught up with
your enthusiasm.
Oh, you beautiful Magnus, get that body into gear, there's not a minute to waste.
I don't think my eyes are awake yet.
Well, mine are, and you look marvelous.
We'd better get to the stable.
Our animal friends will be hungry right about now.
I'm pretty hungry, too.
Well, thanks to our early breakfast friend, breakfast is ready and waiting.
Star got up early, cooked breakfast, and set the table.
Let's grab some to go, Gertie.
The animals sound like they're about to revolt, and you know they really need a stable diet.
But wait, before we go about our chores, I just want to take a moment and celebrate.
What's to celebrate?
That we're orphans?
It's just another day in Bethlehem.
And here's this ray of sunshine.
Everyone, this is our newest guest.
We found him wandering around town last night, and we invited him.
That's how we all got here.
Trixie had room with her in, and now we're one.
Big!
Happy!
Did they stay with us for a while?
Only because I assumed it would be less noisy than the streets.
Well, my slightly grumpy new friend, I am also glad you could stay with us today, because...
Is she always this perky?
Yeah, sometimes even more so.
Today is my one-year anniversary at being here at the Inn of Bethlehem with you fine people.
Hasn't really been here already, Star?
Yeah.
I just want to take a moment to appreciate everyone and everything.
This has been this past year so special.
Did she just boop your nose?
She does that.
You'll get used to it.
Not sure about that.
And what's so special about being here in Bethlehem?
So many things!
And what's so special about being here in Bethlehem with you?
And what's so special about being here in Bethlehem?
Bethlehem?
Love is born, hope is here, Heaven's light has made the darkness disappear.
Peace on earth, good will to men, God with us, all because of Bethlehem.
And what's so special about being here in Bethlehem?
And what's special about being here in Bethlehem?
I'm here in Bethlehem.
Mary, Mary, you found favor with God.
Mary, do not be afraid.
How, oh, how could I not be afraid?
It was an angel.
An angel?
An angel.
She will give birth to a son.
And you will call him Jesus.
He will save his people from their sins.
And they will call him, they will call him, they will call him.
They will call him, they will call him, they will call him.
Emmanuel, Emmanuel.
God with us.
He will keep it.
Emmanuel, Emmanuel.
God with us.
Emmanuel.
He will be great.
You look fine.
Thank you.
Hello.
I'm Tracy.
I run the end of Bethlehem.
Star has told me about your predicament, and I'm really very sorry.
If we could help, we would.
But there really are no names left.
I still know what to do.
Every other end is booked up.
Miss Trixie, I have an idea.
If you want, you can come stay with my amazing animals in the stable.
John, Luke, and I keep it pretty clean in there, and I can make sure that animals are really
well-behaved.
Plus, my animal car could sing to you.
Huh?
That's very generous.
Thank you.
Follow me.
Can you believe it?
I knew this was going to be a day to remember.
I've always had a certain way of knowing when the day's going to be incredible.
I can tell these things, you know?
Don't you always think the day is going to be incredible?
Well, yeah.
But it always is!
Well, I got then settled in the stable, but I don't think that baby's going to wait much longer.
So exciting!
What a blessed day!
Listen, Perky, you gotta dial it down.
I've been on my own for a while, and I can tell you, things are not as awesome as you think.
What do you mean?
This is an ordinary inn, it's not a special day, and even...
Those animals don't sing, and even though you think you have a family here, you're still an orphan.
Okay, this is great!
Just saying, as soon as I can earn some more money here, I'll be getting straight out of Bethlehem.
Not sure where I'm going.
I've been around.
There's nothing here for me.
I won't stay in this town anymore.
Anymore.
Don't need no sympathy.
I've gotten this bar.
I've been around. There's nothing here for me. I won't stay in this town anymore. Anymore.
Don't need no sympathy. I've gotten this part. I've got a strategy. Don't let down my God anymore. Anymore.
Someday I'll find a place in my mind. But now it's only a dream. Where I can just breathe and be me.
A place to be alone. Don't have to be strong. Where life is not filled with pain.
A place to be free. A place to be free.
But for now here I am. All alone.
Someday you'll feel a love that is real. For one who knows who you are.
Who created the star and the star.
Someday you'll know he'll never let go. For he knows you by name.
A place to be free. A place to believe.
But for now here I am. All alone.
All lately. I think you just need some friends to surround you and tell them you how much they care about you.
Come on everyone. Gather around.
That's okay. I'm fine. I always am.
Hey what about those two people that were talking about seeing angels?
I mean seriously. Angels? Surely you can't believe in them.
Of course I believe in them.
Let's think logically Blake. Both Mary and Joseph both saw angels at different times who told them the same thing.
What are the chances that two different people would see angels?
We've just seen an angel!
Conscience of angels. It was terrifying.
They told us the savior was to be born tonight.
See? Someone else saw angels tonight.
We sure did. Let me give you the skin.
Ooh I found another story coming on.
Man. They were just appearing left and right and it really psyched yourself and we were like whoa.
And the angel was like can you dig it?
Like what?
We were chillaxing in the field with our sheep like they always do when we saw a funky groovy sight.
And we were bugging out cause a glowing cold hat was boogieing all over to us and I was like dino much.
This angel was up in my face.
Then we froze in fear because the angel spoke and that righteous angel said this will be a sign unto you.
You will find a child wrapped in bands of clothes and lying in a manger.
There was with the angel a multitude of the heavenly host praising God saying glory to God in the highest and on earth peace to men on him in the favor of Christ.
When those cool cats had left us and gone into heaven we said to one another let's keep on trucking to Bethlehem and see this thing that has taken place.
The Lord has made known to us.
Don't worry.
I'm not going to preach a full sermon.
I don't think.
But I did want to share just a few thoughts.
And also, the kids who worked so very hard are having a cast party in the kids' room
with hot chocolate and candy and fun things.
And so, if all I am doing is buying them time to get their well-deserved party,
then I think that is a good thing.
But hopefully, the Lord has given me some things that might encourage you this morning.
I don't know about you, but I cannot believe that it's just a few days away from Christmas.
Who still has some things left to do?
Shopping.
Wrapping.
Okay.
Real people, real lives.
Everybody can put their hands up.
Nobody's going to judge you.
It's fine.
Yeah.
I can't believe it's happened this quickly.
This week, we are going to light our next-to-last Advent candle as we are building the anticipation
of lighting the Christ candle on Christmas Eve.
If you don't have any plans for Christmas Eve, I would love for you to join us.
And we've been going through this process of lighting the candles of Advent.
We said that Advent is really about remembering that the light of the world has come through the birth of Jesus.
We look back to the past to see that God has been faithful in his promise in the past.
Not only that, but he's invited us to participate in being a light to the world in the present.
So he has come in the past.
He has spread his light to those of us who have received the gospel message.
And he's invited us not just to look back and to look forward, but to play a part in being the light of the world to those around us.
That's what the kids were doing this morning.
They're a light.
They're shining in our congregation, retelling us the message of the hope of Jesus in a way that is apparently straight out of Bethlehem.
I'm so excited about that.
And Star, is she coming for my job?
Is that what's happening here?
Because I don't like, I'm not, wow, I think I'm a little intimidated right now.
So let's really quickly recap the candles that we've litten so far.
The first candle is the candle of hope.
We said that hope is not just confident expectation, but intentional participation in the promises of God.
During our Watts Week, we lit the candle of love, and we said that biblical love is most clearly demonstrated in sacrificial presence.
God being with us, God being Emmanuel, is clearly demonstrating God's love.
Every time I bend down, I realize I'm showing you guys my bald spot, and that's a little bit insecure for me.
So, tech team, I just complimented you.
Turn that camera off when I bend down.
Biblical love is most clearly demonstrated through sacrificial presence.
And last week, we looked at biblical joy, and we said that joy is rooted in God's grace given to us.
And this morning, we light the last candle prior to the Christ candle on Christmas Eve, and that will be the candle that represents the peace of Jesus.
Maybe.
You know what?
It might happen, it might not.
It has to happen.
Y'all, pray this candle to light.
There we go.
We got it.
All right.
Let's pray.
Father in heaven, so grateful for this morning that we get to just witness the gifts that you've given to our family of God through these children.
God, what beautiful, wonderful blessings they are to us.
God, I thank you that they have spent months meditating on what the story of Christmas means and how to portray it in a way that's fun and exciting for them to display it and for us to receive it.
And I pray that this time this morning that we have together would be encouraging and will remind us of what this season really is all about.
In Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
I follow a stand-up comedian who's the son of a very large church pastor.
And I came across a bit that he was doing a couple months ago and he said, you know, comedians, essentially he was saying that pastors have like a much harder job than stand-up comedians.
He was like, as a stand-up comedian I can come up on stage, I can talk about literally anything I want and make it funny.
He said, my dad, on the other hand, for the last 30 years has had to stand up every Sunday and give a book report on the same book.
He's like, how hard is that?
Like every Sunday you've got to stand up and give your book report on the same book.
And I laughed at that and I often, I don't often feel that tension, but during the holidays I feel like I feel that tension more than any other time of the year.
Jesus was born.
The tomb is empty.
There's only so many ways that you can teach these ideas, right?
Like these stories come up every single year, year in and year out.
And how, how can I portray them in a new and fresh way?
And I keep telling myself that you guys probably don't remember what I said last year.
So I could say it again and it would be fine, but I just, I don't feel good about that.
So as I was thinking about peace this year, I kept coming back to this primary Christmas text about peace.
Even if you didn't grow up in church, you've probably heard it quoted from time to time.
A child is born.
A son is given.
The government will be on his shoulders.
He will be called the Prince of Peace.
His government and its peace will never end.
He will rule with fairness and justice from the throne of his ancestor, David.
This is the famous Christmas passage on peace that many of us are familiar with.
And I just didn't feel like I could do it justice in a short amount of time.
There's so many deep implications for our lives in that passage.
And so I was like, okay, I can't do that.
So I thought some more.
I prayed some more.
And as I meditated, I thought about how most of the messianic prophecies in the Old Testament,
many of them are connected to, they are rooted to a specific character in the Old Testament.
And that is King David.
And that was in this passage here, connected to King David.
That King David was just, in many ways, a shadow of who Jesus would ultimately come to be.
Not just for the nation of Israel, but for the entire world.
As I thought about King David, and I thought about the messianic prophecy about peace,
I was reminded that David has two primary vocational roles.
One being king, that is connected to this prophecy.
Anybody know the other vocational role that David had?
Feel confident they want to scream it out?
Shepherd.
See, somebody's brave.
I like that.
I'm proud.
David had two primary vocational roles.
He was king, and he was intended to bring peace and fairness and justice to the nation of Israel.
But before that, he was a shepherd.
And as a shepherd of his flock, his job was to bring peace to the flock,
to ensure that they had everything that they needed.
And in Ezekiel, we actually have kind of this messianic imagery about the Messiah coming to be,
in some ways, a shepherd.
It says this in Ezekiel 34, verse 11 and 12.
It says, "I myself, Yahweh, will come and I will find my sheep.
I will be like a shepherd looking for his scattered flock.
I myself will tend my sheep and give them a place to lie down in peace," says the Sovereign Lord.
And then we have Jesus coming onto the scene, and he often looks at people who don't have much peace at all,
people who are anxious, people who are like our friend Blake,
who are beaten down by the circumstances of the world, who are orphans,
who don't have a home or a place to lie their head.
He looks at these people and he says he has compassion on them because they are like sheep without a shepherd.
Jesus would go on in one of the famous "I am" statements in John to say, "I am the good shepherd."
So Jesus comes like a king who is going to put the government on his shoulders,
who is going to bring about cosmic peace and justice in the world,
but he also comes to each one of us like individual sheep as a shepherd to bring us to peace,
to lead us to peace.
So with the rest of our brief time together, I want to meditate on how Jesus coming to be our good shepherd
can lead us into lasting peace.
If you're in here this morning and you're struggling to have peace,
you're like Blake and you're like, "Okay, you guys are all chipper and happy and excited,
but I just can't put a fake smile on anymore."
If you're like that, is it possible that maybe you're operating your life like a sheep without a shepherd?
And maybe, just maybe, this baby that we spend our entire morning meditating on,
maybe he truly is the good shepherd that can lead you into peace.
So, what exactly is peace?
And how might the imagery of a good shepherd help us understand or even experience biblical peace?
When I think about peace, typically I think about what Michelle is experiencing right now, right?
It's like the relief of the thing that was bothering you so much finally going away.
Peace is that deep breath that we can take and feel like, "Okay, there's an absence of tension or conflict in my life."
And that's a good feeling. We all want that feeling. We all chase that feeling.
But we often know, most of us probably know, that that feeling does not last very long.
Especially on this side of heaven, right?
We might have a deep breath here or there, but what's going to happen to Michelle is what's going to happen to all of us.
She's going to take a deep breath and realize the Christmas play is over.
And then she's going to come in Monday morning and I'm going to assign her a sermon for the month of January.
And she is no longer going to have peace.
Don't tell her. It'll be fine. I'm just kidding. I already told her.
So I know right now she's experiencing temporary peace, that that peace is not going to last for very long.
And this is what we tend to think about when we think about peace, the absence of conflict or tension.
But biblical peace goes a bit further. Biblical peace includes the idea of wholeness or completeness.
The word in the Hebrew for peace is shalom and it literally means lacking nothing.
I don't know about you, but I rarely have the experience of lacking nothing.
We have a constant list of stress and to-dos filling our heads.
Things that we think we should be doing, but don't have the energy to do.
Relational stress, tension, on and on we could go.
We all wrestle with struggle to experience this feeling of lacking nothing.
And this experience would be the constant experience of any sheep who did not have a good shepherd.
Sheep without a shepherd are constantly in survival mode.
They're just trying to avoid predators while finding clean, reliable sources of food and water.
They might stumble into safety or a solid food source from time to time.
But that experience is temporary.
It will not last very long.
Their normal experience is tension and anxiety, constantly just trying to survive.
Searching but never finding.
Can any of you this morning relate to the experience of a sheep without a shepherd?
Do any of us feel burnout, worn down, exhausted?
Maybe we stumble into periods of peace here and there.
But how often do we experience this lasting peace?
The Bible calls it a peace that passes understanding.
A peace that isn't impacted by the circumstances around us, but a peace that lasts.
How often do we experience that peace?
So, my main point for this morning is this.
Earthly peace can be achieved through aggression or avoidance,
but biblical peace is received through submission and obedience.
A sheep without a shepherd can at times achieve peace through fighting or through avoiding, right?
Through being aggressive or through avoiding any and all predators or from hiding or from being safe.
They might achieve peace temporarily, and so it is with us.
We might be able to achieve an experience of peace here and there from time to time,
but in order for us to do that, we often have to fight back against our enemies or avoid our enemies altogether.
Achieving peace on earth is an exhausting experience.
We have to fight for it.
We have to work hard for it, and the moment that we think we have it,
there's something lurking in the background that we feel like might take it away.
Earthly peace is fleeting and exhausting because it constantly has to be achieved.
And I said aggressive, but some of us in here maybe achieve it through passive aggressiveness.
Right?
You're like, that's not me.
I don't fight back.
Hmm.
All right.
Well, let's throw in there passive aggressive for you as well.
Right?
Like there's this way we go about trying to find peace.
If someone insults us, we insult them back.
Someone gossips, we return the favor.
An eye for an eye.
But here's the problem with that approach is that if your goal is peace, you cannot stop fighting back until you've overpowered every person or thing that is in the way of your peace.
Always looking over your shoulder for the next threat, just like a sheep without a shepherd.
You might be able to experience pockets or periods of peace, but that peace will not last very long.
If you feel like you don't have what you need, you don't have proper food or water sources, you work harder, you sacrifice more, you lose appreciation for what you have out of the pursuit of more constantly chasing that feeling of having what you think you need and never actually achieving it.
Earthly peace, it can be achieved, but only temporarily through aggression or through avoidance.
See, the alternative to fighting back would be my favorite approach, which is avoiding conflict altogether.
Any peace keepers in the room or am I the only one?
Cool.
Just me.
All right.
Well, I wrote it in my notes.
I'm going to read it anyway.
The alternative to fighting back, to getting into conflict, to overpowering our enemies is to avoiding tension and conflict altogether, to totally running away from conflict.
And again, we might experience partial peace this way, but it's draining because we actually aren't getting what we need.
We're not being honest about the circumstances or realities of life.
We're avoiding conflict that is there, pretending like it's not there.
We might experience partial peace for temporary periods of time by avoiding or by being aggressive, but at the end of the day, it's temporary.
A sheep without a shepherd, they might be able to avoid predators for a certain period of time, but eventually they will starve to death because in order to avoid predators, they have to put themselves far, far away from food sources, from food and water.
And how often, even in our relationships, those of us who are avoidance people, how often do we actually not have what we need in the relationships that we want because we're not honest with the people we're in relationship with.
Earthly peace.
It can be achieved through aggression or avoidance, but it's temporary.
It isn't lasting.
On the other hand, biblical peace is secure because it isn't achieved by our efforts.
Rather, it is received as we learn to submit and be obedient to the good shepherd, going where he wants us to go, even when it doesn't make sense.
So, famous psalm.
You guys might know where I'm going.
King David, whose many of the messianic promises are rooted in a psalm that talks about peace as his experience as a shepherd.
It says this in Psalm 23:1, "The Lord is my shepherd.
I have all that I need.
He lets me rest in green meadows.
He leads me beside peaceful streams.
He renews my strength.
He guides me along right paths, bringing honor to his name.
Even when I walk through the darkest valley, I will not be afraid.
For you are close behind me.
Your rod and your staff, they protect and they comfort me.
You prepare a feast before me in the presence of my enemies.
You honor me by anointing my head with oil.
My cup overflows with blessings.
Surely your goodness and unfailing love will pursue me all the days of my life.
And I will live in the house of the Lord forever."
This is David poetically explaining what he feels like it is to be led by Yahweh as good shepherd.
As his own experience of leading his sheep to places of peace, of having a plan, of having an idea of where they're going, of knowing that he can protect them from danger.
Knowing that he can lead them to the place of green pastures.
He can get them through the darkest valleys to get them to the place where he needs to be.
This is what it is to be led by God as a good shepherd.
See, with a good shepherd, they don't feel the need to fight back because they have a good shepherd yielding a rod of justice.
See, if we've been mistreated, if we've been abused, if we've been neglected, we don't have to fight back.
Those of us that have submitted our lives to Jesus as the good shepherd, we know that our good shepherd is a good shepherd of justice.
And ultimately, he will take care of all of the injustices in the world.
We don't have to fight back against our enemies.
We don't have to yield a rod because our shepherd yields a rod of justice.
We don't have to avoid the dark valleys because we can entrust ourselves to his nurture and care.
We know that he is going to lead us to the place that we need to go.
We never get too far out of safety because we willingly receive correction from his gentle staff.
He carries a rod and a staff.
The rod is for our enemies and the staff is for us.
When we get off track, when we move too far away from his plans or his purposes, he lovingly corrects us.
And if we're willing to receive that correction, we will never get too far out of safety.
Because he has our best interest in mind.
The Lord is our shepherd.
We have all that we need.
Isn't that the definition of peace?
Isn't that biblical shalom?
Wholeness, completeness, having everything that we need.
If we want peace, we have to stop trying to achieve it through our own means
and we have to sit back and allow Jesus as our good shepherd to lead us through the circumstances of our life
and to bring about peace for us.
Remember at the beginning of my short talk, I was referencing the most famous Christmas passage about peace.
Well, there's one other Christmas passage about peace that we read a lot.
And we've read it last week in the angel's announcement to the shepherd.
It says this, "Glory to God in the highest heaven and peace on earth to those with whom God is well pleased."
I don't think it's ironic that the first official announcement of the birth of the good shepherd
was announced to shepherds who provided peace for their flock, but had no one to provide peace for them.
These shepherds were themselves like sheep without a shepherd, but everything was about to change.
This announcement is the beginning of what Ezekiel prophesied.
God himself came looking for his scattered flock, and he is still doing so today.
We have a good shepherd who is gathering for himself his flock who are willing to submit and to obey him,
even when it doesn't make sense.
Even when he has us walk through the valley of the shadow of death.
Are we willing to submit and obey him, even when our enemies fight back against us?
Even when the circumstances of our life are not leading us to have the things that we need?
Are we willing to trust him?
This is what the Bible says, that we can have a peace that passes understanding
if we willingly submit and obey Jesus.
So are you exhausted from trying to achieve peace on your own?
Stop fighting your enemies.
Love them.
Pray for them and entrust yourself to the good shepherd who yields the rod of justice.
Justice is his job, not ours.
Stop avoiding conflicts or trials and step into them with grace and truth.
Be honest with the people around you about the things that they're doing that hurt you,
but do so with grace and with truth.
Don't avoid conflict, but lean into it with the grace of God.
The good shepherd will lead you through the shadow of the valley of death and into greener pastures.
Our good shepherd has something so much more for us than just the absence of conflict or tension.
Again, when we submit our lives to Jesus as the good shepherd.
Excuse me, wow.
Psalm 23 says, "He will give us all that we need."
This is shalom, this is true peace.
When we give up our ability to earn it for ourselves and when we sit back and receive it from God.
Biblical peace is received through submission and obedience to Jesus as our good shepherd.
Let's pray.
Father in heaven.
We thank you that you give us all that we need.
And we acknowledge that we are so easily tempted to try and go get it for ourselves.
To try and fight back against our enemies.
To try and avoid conflict at all costs.
To try and hold things together as much as we can.
Let's get through this holiday season and then we can take a deep breath.
No, that is false peace.
That does not last.
God, may we receive from you a lasting peace that passes all understanding.
May we be willing to submit our lives to you.
May we be willing to follow you even when it doesn't make sense.
May we be willing to do this for us.
Have a great week.
And hopefully we'll see you in a couple of days.
For our Christmas Eve service.
May we be willing to do this for us.